Hi guys, and welcome to the ASP.Net Core MVC up and running course.
This will be part one of the two courses.
My name is Brogan and I will be your instructor for this course.
In this course, we will focus on the basics of ASP.Net Core MVC as we will start building real world
application.
That being said, we will dive into some intermediate concepts in ASP.Net Core MVC as we will work through
the course.
Before you take this course, you should be familiar with the basics of C Sharp and SQL.
I would say about six months of experience with both should be sufficient.
That being said, let's take an overview of what are the basic topics that will be covered in this course.
We will start with the basic foundation of ASP.Net Core MVC project as we will explore files and folder
structure with the basic concepts like middleware, pipeline routing and much more.
Then we will be pushing models to database using entity framework core.
After that, our first task will be to perform Crud operations using ASP.Net Core, MVC and Entity Framework
Core.
Once we build a good foundation with the basics, we will dive into more advanced topics like session
forms, view data, view back validations and much more.
We will be adding security to our project and for that we will be adding ASP.Net Identity Razor class
library to the project manually and we will see how we have to configure the changes.
We will add multiple roles in our website and much more.
Finally, as our real world application evolves, we will see how to send email and use email templates
along with all the topics we cover.
One of the most important topic is assignments and error solving.
I try to show the most common errors that you face while building a net core project and how to resolve
these errors along with plenty of handfull assignments.
That being said, we have lots of exciting things in this course.
But first let me show you the demo of the application that we will be building in this course in the
next video.