In this video.
Before we take a look at the other files, I will introduce you to a new concept, which is dependency
injection.
ASP.Net Core implements a simple built in dependency injection container.
Dependency injection is an integral part of ASP.Net Core architecture.
Dotnet Core injects objects of dependency classes through constructor by using the built in IOC container.
That being said, let me try to explain in simple words what dependency injection is and what benefit
it brings.
Let's consider a scenario without dependency injection.
So in any application, let's say we have three pages right now and we have some common functionality
that we want to use across all the three pages like email and database access.
Now let's imagine that on all of these pages, we need access to database first.
So what we will do is we will create the database object on all the three pages, and in our case,
we'll call the class name as DB.
Then we'll have to do the same and create object of the email implementation that we have in all the
three pages for the email class.
Now consider a scenario What happens if in future you change the implementation of how you access the
database or email based on the current configuration, You might have to make changes in all the three
pages, which is a big mess.
Another issue here is on each page you have to deal with creating the object, managing them as well
as disposing them, and that would consume time in each and every page, which is a bad approach.
So that being said, what is a solution to avoid all of this?
The answer is dependency injection with dependency injection.
Let's first see how this scenario would look like.
We will again have all the three pages and the email and database functionality here, along with all
the things that we had before.
We will have something new, which is a dependency injection container.
Then we will have the email and database functionality, but rather than having them in just classes,
we will also have an interface for email and database.
Then our classes will be implementing those interface and we will register the interfaces in our dependency
injection container as you can see.
So we will tell dependency injection container that email is an interface and email is implementation
of that interface.
When any page will need to access these functionalities, it will just ask the dependency injection
container to create object of this functionality and directly give us the object to use.
So inside the page we will actually be using interfaces and then dependency injection does all its magic
of passing the object when the website needs it.
That way we do not have to deal with creating the object, disposing or managing that object inside
our pages.
Our pages will look very clean with just the interface and all the instance and implementation will
be done by the dependency injection container.
Now, in future, if you want to change or replace the email class, you do not have to make any change
in the pages.
All you have to do is you just need to change the implementation that you do in the dependency injection
container in one location.
Also, as I have said before, creating and disposing object is now the responsibility of the built
in dependency injection container and we do not have to worry about it anymore, which is a great relief.
So you can see that there are lots of advantages that dependency injection brings to the architecture.
That being said, with Dotnet core, we have the built in dependency injection container.
Now how do we register this dependencies or where do we register these dependencies?
Let's understand a part of that in the next video.