We had to take a detour to understand dependency injection before we understand the next file, which
is startup right here.
You can right click here and go to the definition, or you can open up the startup file from here itself.
Now, startup class, as you can see, is a basic class with no extensions or implementations of interface.
But the first thing that you notice if you scroll down is that there are two methods.
The first one is the configure services and the next one is the configure method.
Both of these methods are invoked automatically by ASP.Net Core.
Configure services gets called first.
We will be registering all the dependencies with dependency injection container that is built in in
ASP.Net Core within the configure services.
So that is why I wanted to introduce you to dependency injection in the previous video, because configure
services is the place where you do the registration of your service.
If we switch back to the PowerPoint, the step that we do when we register our email and database with
interface as well as the implementation, that is the step that we will do inside configure services
method.
So inside the configure services method, we can add services to the collection of services.
Services are basically any functionality that you want to register so other parts of application can
use it.
As we saw, it could be email database and much more.
We will be registering the services provided by the Dotnet core framework as well as custom services
that we will create.
As of now, you can see right here we just have one services which is add controllers with views.
And with this we register MVC service to our application.
We will be adding more services here.
But before we dive into MVC in the next video, let's understand the configure method.
But remember that configure services method gets called by the runtime and we use this method to add
services to our container.
That being said, let's continue in the next video.