In the last video, we took a look at configure services.
Next method that we have here is the configure method.
Here we see the AI application builder as well as the AI web host environment.
Environment We are using only to check if it's development or if it's something else.
Based on that, we are configuring the pipeline, but the AI application builder configures the Http
request pipeline of ASP.Net Core.
The pipeline specifies how the application should respond to each Http request.
Let's take a look at this with an example.
So in order to understand what the pipeline is, let me switch to the presentation here.
We have different browsers here and then we have a pipeline.
The pipeline specifies how the application should respond to each Http request.
When your application receives a request from the browser, the request goes back and forth through
the pipeline.
In the pipeline.
You can add items that you want.
Pipeline is made up of Middlewares and MVC is a middleware itself.
So if we want an application to be built using MVC, we need to add that middleware.
Other examples could be authentication, middleware authorization, middleware, session middleware,
static files, middleware and much more.
So what exactly happens is when your request will go through each middleware, it can get modified by
them and eventually it is either passed to the next middleware.
And if that is the last middleware in the pipeline, the response is returned back to the server.
Let's take a look at the few middlewares that are already added in our application.
So if we switch back to the code inside the configure method first, we are checking.
If the environment is development, then we are adding a middleware for developer exception page.
Else we have the exception handler which displays a custom error message because we do not want to show
them the developer or the coding error.
Then the next middleware is use https redirection.
This forces the user to use a secure line and then we are adding static files.
What I mean by static files is that any web project needs styling, JavaScript images and much more.
So all of the static content will be served by our application only because we added the middleware
to use the static files.
Then we are adding the routing middleware followed by authorization middleware.
You can see authorization is added before the end points right here.
And that is because order matters when it comes to the middleware.
When a request comes in, it is passed from the first middleware to the second to the third, and so
on.
In End Point, we configure the default route for our application.
That being said, before we understand the end points in more detail, let me explain you routing in
the next video.