Inside the configure method.
We have seen the use routing as well as use endpoints.
That being said, we haven't seen the actual MVC routing and how that works.
Endpoint routing has been introduced in ASP.Net Core three.
In the initial version of ASP.Net Core, routing was a part of MVC, but it has been separated out to
make routing available to all the Middlewares and not just MVC.
Whenever a request comes in, it hits an endpoint and that endpoint is processed by the middleware.
Before we get into those details, let me switch to presentation and I can give you an example of routing.
The URL pattern for routing is considered after the domain name.
So in this case it will be after localhost and the port number, which is five, five, five five.
Then in the example URL that we have, we see category forward slash index, forward slash three.
In an MVC application, the first thing that you will see will be the name of the controller.
After that, we will have the name of the action followed by the ID.
Also keep in mind that ID is an optional field.
Some of these fields can be optional and if they are not present, it will take the default value.
Like if an action name is missing, it will default the action name to be index.
You can change the defaults if you want, but if we switch back to our application and if we see the
endpoint that we are using, we have a default pattern in which we have the controller name defaulted
to home action name defaulted to index, and we have an ID property which is optional.
So with that in place, let's try to see some more examples here.
The first example we have forward slash category, forward slash index.
So in that case category will be the controller index will be the action.
We do not have anything for the ID, so ID will be null.
Next, what we have is only category.
In that case the controller will be category controller and action will be defaulted to index action.
And if no ID is present, it will be null.
Then we have category forward slash edit forward slash three.
We have all the fields here.
Controller will be category and it will be the action and id will be three.
In the last example, we have product forward slash details, forward slash three.
Again, we have all the three entities.
Controller will be the product action will be details and ID will be three.
Now in MVC there is a route table which tries to match end points to find out where to pass the request
to be on track here.
If we have a URL like this in MVC, home would point to a controller and index would point to an action
method as we saw in the last slide.
Now, if you are not aware about what is a controller, what is an action method?
Do not worry right now.
Just understand that this is one way of routing.
We will be getting into MVC details very shortly, but ASP.Net Core is now more than just an MVC application.
It can also have razor pages and SignalR.
That being said, it is possible to have all three in a single application.
All of these technologies have middlewares that register endpoints.
So if we switch back to our application right here, we see a middleware of use routing in Startup.cs.
So let's imagine at some point we hit this middleware.
At this point, the request will inspect all of the registered endpoints.
They can be endpoints registered by MVC or any other technology.
It determines whether it should send the request to MVC or any other technology.
Then for all the middlewares that will be executed after this, we will know that endpoint has been
selected like MVC or Razor pages.
And then later on, when it hits the endpoint in the use endpoints, we will register the endpoint and
then when the request arrives, at this point it will be processed by the endpoint that was selected
in use routing.
So in the expression we have the endpoints and we have an object for the options on this object, there
are several extension methods that are available to register different.
Endpoints like right here we are registering the MVC.
Then we have other endpoints for Razor and SignalR as well.
We will be adding razor endpoint later in the course and within the controller, which is the MVC,
we have added a default pattern.
So by default it will load the home controller and index action if nothing has been loaded.
So here we also have registered a default route for MVC application, which has a controller name home
and an action method called as index.
This map controller route uses routing table to match against the request.
This is the basic overview of routing middleware that we have.
That being said, before I actually run the application and walk you through routing in demo, let me
finish the overview of the other files and then we'll get back to routing and view it live in action.