Next.
What we want to see here is we have a folder called w w, w Root.
This folder has been created since we selected the MVC application.
In here, if you expand this, there are more folders that has static files for our application.
Static files could be CSS, JavaScript or any of the third party libraries.
You can also have images here or HTML templates.
If you remember in Startup.cs, if we go there, we added a middleware use static files and that was
added so that the application can use the static files that we add inside W.w.w root.
This W.w.w root folder will be the root folder in application for all static files.
None of the C sharp files will be placed in this folder.
This folder is only meant to serve all the static files for our application.
So we'll be using the static files folder extensively throughout the course when we have to add images
or we want to add any class libraries or we want to modify external CSS.
Once we have that, the last thing that we have is launch Settings.json.
Launch Settings.json is inside the properties folder and if we double click it displays different profile
in which we can run the application.
Like here, if the profile is IIS express, it sets the environment variable for that profile to be
development.
This way you can configure more profiles that you want with the URL as a support and other functionalities.
Also, when we will run the application right here, we will be seeing all the profiles that we have
set up inside the launch settings.
So right here you can see IIS express and we have the rocky profile URL.
If you want to modify them, you can modify here directly or you can also do the same.
If you right click here and here.
If you go to the properties, we will be having those profiles in the debug tab.
So right here you see IIS Express as well as Rocky.
We can set the browser URL and we can set the environment variables that we want.
Here we have the other settings which you can set from that page or we can do in the launch settings
dot Json.
Now we won't be tweaking this much because this is more related to deployment.
And if you want to add more environment variable for like staging another environment, but we'll just
keep it with the basic for this course.