So with that, we have covered all of the files that we see in the project except three main folders,
which is controllers, models and views.
And as you would have guessed, this is what MVC stands for, which is model view and controller.
That being said, let's understand the architecture of an MVC application.
The first thing in MVC is the model.
Model represents the shape of the data.
A class in C sharp is used to describe a model.
The model component corresponds to all the data related logic that user works with.
This can represent either the data that is being transferred between view and controller or any business
logic related data model would also represent all the tables of the database.
So if you have ten tables in the database, you will have at least ten models on top of that.
There is also more complexity, but we will go into those details later on in the course.
So if a class is a model, then all the properties in that class will be all the columns of a table.
So that is the simple relation that you can think about model right now.
Then we have the view.
View in an MVC is a user interface view.
Basically means whatever you see when you click a web page, the UI that you see that will be represented
by The View.
View in ASP.Net MVC is HTML, CSS and some special syntax, which is razor syntax.
So main thing about view is that it represents the user interface logic of your application.
Finally, we have the controller.
The controller handles the user request.
Typically whenever a request comes in like user clicks anything, it will raise an Http request which
will be handled by the controller.
The controller then uses the model as well as view to process the request and then it returns back an
appropriate response.
So controller acts as an interface between model and view to process all the business logic.
Incoming requests and it manipulates the data using model and interact with the view to render the final
output.
This is just a brief overview of how model, view and controller interacts.
So just to summarize, what happens is first a user clicks something on the website, so a request comes
to controller.
Controller will always be the main entry point in an MVC application and in controller it will hit any
of the action methods that we have defined inside the controller.
Now Controller Will uses the model and it will fetch all the data that it needs to display in a view.
Then it passes that data to the view so that view can render the final page that user can see.
Then view will send the request back to the controller and then based on whatever is rendered, a response
will be sent back and user will be able to see the page.
So you can see controller can be treated as part of your application.
With that in place in the next video, let's run our application for the first time and see how model,
view and controller interacts and how routing works.