Now before I run the application and show you routing in detail, let's take a look at the folders that
we have with model views and controllers.
So right here we have a home controller, and in the model we have the error view model.
Whenever we'll be adding new models or if we want to add a new table in the database, we will be adding
models inside this folder.
Controller, as we know, is the heart of the application in controller.
If you expand this, you see there are many of the functions.
These are known as individual action method.
So a controller has action method.
If we go back to the routing template that we had, we had the controller name and the action name.
So what means is if someone calls index, then they can call it home forward slash index and the control
will hit this breakpoint when the URL is submitted.
And once the control gets here, we are just returning back the View.
So this view will be inside the views folder and inside the home folder.
The folder name will match exactly as the controller name.
So it will look for an index view inside the home folder, inside views, and that will correspond to
the action method that we see right here.
So what we have in the index view is if you open it, we have a title.
We have welcome here.
And then we have learned about building web apps with ASP.Net Core.
Let's run this and make sure that this is actually working.
So let's run our application for the first time and create.
We see that page is loaded.
Now, right here in the URL, we do not see any controller or action name.
And the reason is, if we go back to the application in startup, we configured the default to home
controller index action.
So that being said, if you add a debugging point right here and if you go back and press enter, you
will see that it hits this breakpoint.
So it is actually calling the index action method inside your home controller.
That being said, let's continue here and the view is loaded.
Now, what will happen when we click privacy?
You can see in the URL on the bottom here it is going to home controller and privacy action method.
So right here inside home controller, we have the privacy action method, which just returns back a
view.
That view will again be inside views home.
And we have the privacy view and this is what we should see when we click that.
Let's go back and click here.
Now you can see the control is getting to the privacy action method.
And if you hit continue, the privacy view will be loaded.
Great.
So we can see how routing is working so far.
Right now we do not have any ID, Even if you add an ID, it will still load the privacy because ID
is optional.
So if you have it or if you do not, that doesn't matter.
So with this routing is making a little bit more sense on how the controllers and view routing works.
One thing you should always remember is if your name is home controller, you should have a folder within
the view with the name home, and in there you will add all the views corresponding to the action methods
inside the home controller.
That being said, right here, there are few more views that I want to explain you.
Let me do that in the next video.