In the last video we saw the routing and we saw how the model and views are integrated together.
That being said, in the views, we have a shared folder.
This shared folder is used for partial views.
Partial views are similar to user components if you are coming from classic C sharp.
So it is basically a view that you want to consume in multiple places in your application.
Along with that, we have a special partial view which is underscored layout.
Underscore layout is the default master page for your application.
So in here, if we scroll back to the project that we are running, we have the header here.
So the header and footer are included in underscored layout.
Right here we have the header, then we have render body and we have the footer along with that in underscored
layout, we have some styling and JavaScript that can be used throughout the application.
So in future if you want a styling or a JavaScript functionality that you want to use throughout the
application, this is the place where you will add it.
Other than underscore layout, we have a partial view which is validation scripts.
Partial.
This partial view just has the reference to some of the jQuery for validation.
We will be using this in the future.
Videos.
Then we have an error dot css, HTML and this is just a common error view that we have in developer
mode.
So that's about the shared folder views.
We will be adding more partial views in future.
That being said, inside the views folder, we also have two important files.
First is the view imports.
The purpose of view imports Cshtml file is to provide a mechanism to make directives available to razor
page globally so that you don't have to add them to the pages individually.
So right here it is adding the tag helpers.
So with this, all the default tag helpers that ASP.Net Core team provides will be added to all of the
razor pages in your application.
If you do not have this, then you won't be able to use tag helpers in your project.
An example of tag helpers can be seen in underscored layout.
If we expand the header right here you see this tag helpers ASP area ASP controller ASP action.
These are all the tag helpers that make the binding look like HTML language, but it does the binding
with your C-sharp code tag helpers is an idea that Microsoft team has adopted from other languages after
looking at the success like Angular and React.
So if in future, if you add more custom tag helpers, you can register them here and they will be available
for use throughout the application.
That being said, we'll go to the next file, which is Vue Start.
The main purpose of Vue start is to set values that all the other views will have to use.
If this view exists and it is under the views folder, it enables us to set the property that applies
to all the views in the system right here.
A most common underscored layout view will set some properties.
The default one in MVC is the layout page.
However, you can also do complex thing in Vue start, for example, you can say that for a specific
controller you want to change the layout page, you can add if condition, check the controller name
and do complex logic, but we'll just leave it simple for now.
So here we are defining the default master page for the application is underscored layout right here.
So if you change this, your master page could be changed using the layout property in Vue start.
Also, what you can do is you can add a view, start inside the folder as well and then that file will
take precedence.
So with that, I believe we have covered all the files that we have when the project was created.
Now this has been a lengthy section and it was mostly theoretical with very little exposure to routing
and the project.
But this won't be the same moving forward.
Moving forward, everything will be hands on and we will be coding everything and exploring ASP.Net
Core in detail.
So that being said, let's get started with everything from the next video.