Whenever we are building any project we want to see what is the final application that we will be building.
For that you have to go to Dotnet mastery.com.
And if you go to courses here, you have to select the appropriate course that you are on.
We are on the ASP.Net Core MVC up and running part one.
And when you click on details, we have the live preview.
So let's click there and it will take us to the live preview of the application that we will be building.
Here.
You can see we have filtering on the category for all of the paving stones that we have or that the
customer is selling.
Then for each one of them, you can view the details and you can add them to the shopping cart.
Once you add those, the shopping cart gets populated.
If you go back and try to add it one more time, you do not see that option.
Next option that you see is removed from cart.
Then on the right hand side, you see we have login and registration.
You can always register for a new account for demo purposes.
I have already created two accounts for admin user.
It is admin at gmail and for customer it is user at Gmail.
Let's first log in using the customer account.
So I have entered the username and password and those details are available right here in the info bubble.
You can always create new accounts if you want.
So once we log in as the user, you can see we are back to the home page and if you click on the shopping
cart you can see the products that you added.
Then you can remove the products if you want or you can hit continue here.
When you created the account, you entered name, phone number and email.
So that is populated automatically for you.
You can also change this, but if you think this is good, you can submit an enquiry.
Once you submit an inquiry, an email will be sent out.
Here, I'm just displaying a sample email that will be sent out to the admin user.
It displays a new inquiry, was submitted with customer details and the products they are interested
in.
So that's all the functionalities that a user or a customer can do on our website.
That being said, this is not it.
If we log out and this time let's log in as an admin user.
When you log in as an admin user, you will see there are new tab is available in your navigation bar
and that is content management.
In here you have the category in which you can perform Crud operations on category like create a category,
edit a category or delete any of the existing category.
Now on the demo website I will have disabled the update functionality to avoid misuse of the application.
But here we will be adding validations.
So we'll have Crud operations for category application type and products.
Products will be more complex as compared to category because here we have much more things.
We'll be displaying a rich text box here to add styling.
They can change the image and they have to select category and application type.
Along with that, there will be validations and complex logic that you have to take care of.
So you can always play around with the demo here.
And with the demo, you will always know what is the next step of designing that will be doing.
So that being said, from the next video, let's start with the basics of ASP.Net Core and continue
to build this awesome demo.