Our project has been created and it's time to take a look at the files and folders that we have inside
our project.
The first file will be the project file that we will be taking a look at.
For that, if you right click on the project, you will see the option of edit project file.
Other way of accessing that file is just double click on Rocky.
That will load the project file by default.
Now here in the project file, you should notice the target framework that we are using is net core
app five.
So this will be the dot net framework that we will be using for our solution.
If you are using 3.1 or 3.0, that is the version you will see right here.
Then we have few more elements and the other important entity will be the item group.
Item group will have all of the third party packages that we will be installing in our project.
Right now, when we created the project, we selected the runtime compilation on the project options
because of which it has added that NuGet package right here.
When we will be adding more packages like we'll be adding database packages, email packages, all of
those will be added in the item group and will be watching them once we add new packages in the upcoming
videos.
When you have to add the package, you do not have to come here and manually add the line.
We will be doing that using NuGet packages.
That being said, this looks good for our project file.
Let's continue with the other files in the next video.