Next important file that I want to show you is the Program.cs.
Now, we won't be going through all the files in the same order, but I will be going through them in
an order that will be easier for you to understand.
The next file will be taking a look.
Is the Program.cs.
If we scroll down here, you will see that there is a main method.
Main method is more common in console application, and the reason you see that here is initially Dotnet
core application starts as a console application.
The main method configures ASP.Net Core and starts it.
The configuration is done by calling the create host builder and as you can see, this is a method in
the program class which returns an object of a host builder on this object, build and run are called,
and then onwards the application will become an ASP.Net Core application.
The Create Host Builder calls Default Builder, which configures the web host using defaults.
Also, you can see the web builder is configured using the startup file.
Before we take a look at the startup file in detail, let's understand a core concept of ASP.Net Core,
which is dependency injection.